applicantpro.com 2019-01-13

# Privacy Policy | ApplicantPro

## Privacy & Security Standards:

ApplicantPro is committed to the privacy and security of your personal information. The goal of this policy is to provide you with a clear understanding on how the information that you submit on this site will be used, who this information is shared with and your choices for how to access, update and remove your personal information.

By accessing or using this site, you agree to this Privacy Policy.

## Collecting Information:

Personally identifiable information is collected in a number of sections throughout the ApplicantPro application process. Applicants have the choice to enter information by completing an online application via our applicant tracking system used by our clients. Applicants are not required to give any personal information during the job searching stage of the application process. All information requested directly relates to the job application process. Applicant data is then stored to allow company managers to use during their hiring process and to allow for future position consideration and placement. If you are an applicant, or would like to review our privacy policy specific to applicants, please refer to our [Applicant Information Use & Privacy Policy](https://admin.applicantpro.com/applicant-privacy-policy/).

The personal information you submit to ApplicantPro may include, but is not limited to, your name, address, phone number, email address, usernames, passwords and IP addresses. This information is typically collected when you request a price quote, trial, demonstration or request to sign up for services provided by ApplicantPro. This information will be used only by ApplicantPro to provide you with the requested services and support needed.

## Information Collected Automatically:

We automatically collect information when you use the site such as IP Address, browser types, operating system and device types. This information is used to improve our services and when providing support to our users. Your IP Address may be also used to determine a geolocation that will be used to improve services. Third party tools may be used to collect analytics data such as pages visited and session data. Cookies and other tracking technologies may also be used by ApplicantPro or our by our clients on their career sites and applications. If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so by visiting your browser's cookie settings. Doing so could result in some services not working correctly.

## How your Information will be Used:

How your personal information is used varies depending on your use of this site and our software platform. For client users and general website visitors your information will be used to provide you with the requested services and support needed or requested. We may use information collected automatically to improve your experience as a user or to improve our products and services.

## Protecting Personal Information:

Personally identifiable information is stored on a separate server as a security precaution and our site is SSL encrypted. Since, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information our users transmit to our site; however, we do everything in our power to protect your company and your applicant's information.

All user information is restricted by administrative login to the ApplicantPro applicant tracking system and controlled by the corporate office. Only administrators who have permission are granted access to personally identifiable information. All ApplicantPro employees are kept up-to-date on security and privacy practices. Additionally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment that can only be accessed with a secure login and badge access to the facility.

Data collected by our site is stored at the [DataBank](https://www.databank.com/company.html) data center, located in the US. DataBank uses [multiple layers of security](https://www.databank.com/services/compliance.html) to protect every data center as well as all critical infrastructures supporting the facility. All entrances into secure areas include dual-factor authentication with biometrics and video monitoring captures and stores all entries. DataBank also maintains on-site dedicated security staff to manage surveillance and monitor the secure areas parking and building perimeter. Their site security is managed, maintained and certified in SSAE-16 audits, performed annually at all sites, which confirm their strict adherence to the controls and processes consistently throughout the data center footprint.

## Agreement for Communication:

By filling out a form on our website, you are requesting and providing consent to be contacted by ApplicantPro regarding our products and services. This communication may come in the form of phone calls, emails, postal service mail, or even text messages.

If at any time you would like to stop receiving communication from ApplicantPro, you may email us at [privacy@applicantpro.com](mailto:privacy@applicantpro.com) or call us directly at 888-633-9269 and request that your information be deleted. See Managing your Data below for more information on your choices for data privacy and your right to erasure.

## Data Retention:

We will retain the information associated with your user profile as long as your user account is active. Specific applications submitted to various companies using ApplicantPro will be retained by the employers based on their own data retention policies. We do not maintain complete control over the length of time a company keeps applications on file and this may vary from company to company. Our clients may choose to keep applications on file as they deem reasonably necessary.

## Managing your Data:

Residents of the European Union (EU) have additional rights set forth by the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Although GDPR is intended to protect the personal data of those in the EU, these data management options are available to any users. ApplicantPro acts as the controller of your data. Should you wish to receive an electronic copy of your data or request the removal and erasure of your personal data pertaining to any applications you have submitted through our site or your user profile, you may do so by emailing [privacy@applicantpro.com](mailto:privacy@applicantpro.com) or by calling 888-633-9269.

The removal of your user profile will permanently delete any personal information we have stored for you.

## Children’s Privacy:

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware of data collected from or about children under the age of 13, we will take steps to delete that data from our servers within a reasonable timeframe. Please email [privacy@applicantpro.com](mailto:privacy@applicantpro.com) if you have information about data being collected for children under the age of 13.

## Policy Updates:

This policy may be updated on occasion as we continue to evolve our best practices in securing and protecting your information. Information collected is subject to the Privacy Policy in place at the time it is collected. Keeping your data and your applicants’ data safe is our number one priority. We take this responsibility very seriously and work hard to keep it secure at every level possible. If you have any questions or concerns about any of the information contained in this policy, our security measures, or about our relationship with DataBank, please reach out to our support team by phone at 888-633-9269 or email [privacy@applicantpro.com](mailto:privacy@applicantpro.com).

* * *

* * *
